[
    {
        "question": "Film shooting locales have moved .............. .",
        "options": [
            "Foreign",
            "Gross borders",
            "Overseas",
            "Abroad"
        ],
        "answer":4 
    },
    {
        "question": "Then in 1991, .............. channel showed to the entire world a live visual reporting of the iraq war",
        "options": [
            "CNN",
            "BBC",
            "STAR",
            "SAHARA"
        ],
        "answer":1 
    },
    {
        "question": "The English language has been gaining ground in India due to the process of .............. which began after1990.",
        "options": [
            "Industrialisation",
            "Globalisation",
            "World peace",
            "None of the above"
        ],
        "answer":2 
    },
    {
        "question": "People from different walks of life take, part in the .............. .",
        "options": [
            "Dramas",
            "Agriculture",
            "Theatre",
            "Movies"
        ],
        "answer":1 
    },
    {
        "question": "At global level, Geet Sethi won the .............. billiards competition thrice.",
        "options": [
            "Apprentice.",
            "Amateur",
            "Beginner",
            "Aspirant"
        ],
        "answer":2 
    },
    {
        "question": "In 1998, .............. a private media house entered India.",
        "options": [
            "BBC",
            "CNN",
            "STAR",
            "Zee"
        ],
        "answer":3 
    },
    {
        "question": "During the screening of english movies a short hindi translation now appears on the screen as .............. .",
        "options": [
            "Description",
            "Legend",
            "Sub-titles",
            "Both 1 and 2"
        ],
        "answer":3
    },
    {
        "question": "These Indian languages also have .............. but their number to how on the decline.",
        "options": [
            "Accent",
            "Terminology",
            "Dialects",
            "Vocabulary"
        ],
        "answer":3 
    },
    {
        "question": "We see a reflection of .............. social events, industry and technology in the movies.",
        "options": [
            "Legislature",
            "Politics",
            "Sportsmanship",
            "Diplomatic"
        ],
        "answer":2 
    },
    {
        "question": "At the Olympics of year ................., Karnam Malleshwari won a medal for weightlifting.",
        "options": [
            "2002",
            "2010",
            "1995",
            "2000"
        ],
        "answer":4 
    },
    {
        "question": "The days of a movie running for .............. weeks in one cinema hall are over.",
        "options": [
            "100",
            "50",
            "200",
            "1000"
        ],
        "answer":1 
    },
    {
        "question": "At this stage the world Indian news channels changed .............. .",
        "options": [
            "Drastically",
            "Completely",
            "Fully",
            "None of the above."
        ],
        "answer":2 
    },
    {
        "question": "The age of black and white movies has been .............. by the age of coloured movies accomplish.",
        "options": [
            "Accomplish",
            "Succeeded",
            "Triumph",
            "Projected"
        ],
        "answer":2 
    },
    {
        "question": ".............. came to India during the post-independence period.",
        "options": [
            "Movies",
            "Newspapers",
            "Radios",
            "Television"
        ],
        "answer":4 
    },
    {
        "question": "Production of .............. has attained the status of industry.",
        "options": [
            "Serials",
            "Plays",
            "Movies",
            "Satellites"
        ],
        "answer":3 
    },
    {
        "question": "In 1985, India won the .............. world championship of cricket.",
        "options": [
            "Benson and Hedges",
            "'ITC'",
            "'T20'",
            "Both 1 and 2"
        ],
        "answer":1
    },
    {
        "question": "A few .............. were also produced around the theme of cricket.",
        "options": [
            "Plays",
            "Movies",
            "Theatres",
            "None of the above"
        ],
        "answer":2 
    },
    {
        "question": ".............. and films are important aspects of Indian life.",
        "options": [
            "Dramas",
            "Theatre",
            "Serials",
            "Television"
        ],
        "answer":2 
    },
    {
        "question": "The film industry now employs .............. of people.",
        "options": [
            "Lakhs",
            "Thousand",
            "No.",
            "Crores"
        ],
        "answer":4 
    },
    {
        "question": "During the telecast of .............. and Mahabharat, a majority of the people used to sit glued to the television set.",
        "options": [
            "Ramayana",
            "Vedas",
            "Panchatantra",
            "Jatakas"
        ],
        "answer":1 
    },
    {
        "question": "In the same year, Sunil Gavaskar broke the earlier record of .............. countries, in test cricket.",
        "options": [
            "Minimum",
            "Highest",
            "Lowest",
            "Maximum"
        ],
        "answer":4 
    },
    {
        "question": "During the pre-independence period, only a few selected ............... were known to people is general.",
        "options": [
            "Games",
            "Languages",
            "Technologies",
            "Both 1 and 2"
        ],
        "answer":1 
    },
    {
        "question": "Live .............. of the full five days or one day of the matches also became available.",
        "options": [
            "Projection",
            "Telecasts",
            "Both 1 and 2",
            "None of the above"
        ],
        "answer":2 
    },
    {
        "question": "Now one movie runs in .............. of cinema halls in India and abroad simultaneously.",
        "options": [
            "Hundreds",
            "Thousands",
            "Lakhs",
            "Lakhs"
        ],
        "answer":2 
    }
]